so what's raid 1 reliability if we do
replace failed disks as soon as possible
we have the situation that both disks
are ok
for this amount of time then a disk
fails and then we have only one ok disk
for the mean time to repair for one disk
so this is how long does it take us to
replace the disk
after that
both disks are okay again and then we
again have this long until the next
failure so what's the mean time to data
loss for raid 1 with two disks
the question really is
how many times can we have this until we
encounter the period when a single disk
has failed and during the time it takes
to replace it
another disk fails
well it's equal to the length of this
interval
this is how long we survive with both
disks working times how many times can
we get this until we encounter a repair
period where the second disk fails
during it
so the question is really what's the
probability of the second disk failing
during the time to repair one disk
now normally to calculate this
probability we would have to compute the
distribution for
this function and then see what's the
probability for this distribution being
under empty tr1 and so on but
when
the time to repair is a lot smaller than
the time to failure of a single disk
then we can approximate this probability
of the second disk failing during the
mttr for the first disk
simply as
the mttr divided by the mttf so for
example if the
mttr is let's say a single day and mttf
is a hundred days
then the probability of the second
failure during the repair period is
simply the length of the repair period
divided by the period
that we expected this to survive so for
example if the time to repair is for
example one day
and the time to failure is let's say a
hundred days then we can expect that
there is a one in a hundred chance of a
disk failing
during the one day
so now how many times
can we repair the disk before we
encounter one of these well
the number of times we can try this be
until we encounter a failure is going to
be 1 over this probability
so what we finally get is this
the mean time to data loss is mttf of a
single disk squared divided by two times
the mean time to repair for one disk how
long does it take us to replace the disk
and copy the data on it so that now we
have a fully functional raid1 array and
as a reminder this is how long
do we get a working array with both
disks functional and this is how many
times do we do a repair until we can
expect that the second disk
that is covering us during the repair is
going to fail on us
note that because the mttf
is much larger than the mttr
this is measured in years usually this
hopefully is hours or days it's just how
long does it take us to replace a disk
this factor here is very very large and
now we get many many times
the mttf of a single disk over two this
factor is way larger than two which
means that the time to data loss with
the raid one array with only two disks
is way higher than the time to data loss
for a single disk
which means that raid 1 is dramatically
improving reliability